{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"conduction.",
					"evaporation.",
					"radiation.",
					"convection."
				],
				"question": "The transfer of heat to circulating air, such as when cool air moves across the body’s surface, is called:",
				"source": "See Cold Exposure"
			},
			"back": "convection."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"chest",
					"abdomen",
					"extremities",
					"head"
				],
				"question": "Covering a patient’s _________ will significantly minimize radiation heat loss.",
				"source": "See Cold Exposure"
			},
			"back": "head"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"into the patient’s rectum.",
					"behind the patient’s knee.",
					"under the patient’s armpit.",
					"under the patient’s tongue."
				],
				"question": "To obtain the most accurate reading of a patient’s core body temperature, you should place a special hypothermia thermometer:",
				"source": "See Cold Exposure"
			},
			"back": "into the patient’s rectum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"respiration and bradycardia.",
					"hyperventilation and tachycardia.",
					"perspiration and tachycardia.",
					"sweating and vasodilation."
				],
				"question": "The two most efficient ways for the body to eliminate excess heat are:",
				"source": "See Heat Exposure"
			},
			"back": "sweating and vasodilation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"nausea.",
					"hot, dry skin.",
					"dry tongue and thirst.",
					"tachycardia."
				],
				"question": "Common signs and symptoms of heat exhaustion include all of the following, except:",
				"source": "See Heat Exposure"
			},
			"back": "hot, dry skin."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"decompression.",
					"barometric pressure.",
					"rapid ascent.",
					"rapid descent."
				],
				"question": "A dysbarism injury refers to the signs and symptoms related to changes in:",
				"source": "See High Altitude"
			},
			"back": "barometric pressure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"abdominal or joint pain.",
					"difficulty with vision.",
					"tightness in the chest.",
					"dizziness and nausea."
				],
				"question": "The most prominent symptom of decompression sickness is:",
				"source": "See Diving Emergencies"
			},
			"back": "abdominal or joint pain."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"laryngospasm that protects the lungs from water.",
					"increases in the metabolic rate and oxygen demand.",
					"bradycardia and a slowing of the metabolic rate.",
					"tachycardia and a lowering of the blood pressure."
				],
				"question": "The diving reflex might allow a person to survive extended periods of submersion in cold water secondary to:",
				"source": "See Drowning"
			},
			"back": "bradycardia and a slowing of the metabolic rate."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"radiation.",
					"evaporation.",
					"conduction.",
					"convection."
				],
				"question": "High air temperature reduces the body’s ability to lose heat by:",
				"source": "See Heat Exposure"
			},
			"back": "radiation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Local swelling and ecchymosis",
					"General weakness and diaphoresis",
					"Syncope and bleeding at distal sites",
					"Signs and symptoms of hypoperfusion"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following is an early sign of pit viper envenomation?",
				"source": "See Bites and Envenomation"
			},
			"back": "Local swelling and ecchymosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"convection.",
					"conduction.",
					"radiation.",
					"evaporation."
				],
				"question": "High humidity reduces the body’s ability to lose heat through:",
				"source": "See Heat Exposure"
			},
			"back": "evaporation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"radiation.",
					"convection.",
					"conduction.",
					"evaporation."
				],
				"question": "When a warm hand is immersed in water that is 70°F (21°C), heat is transferred from the hand to the water through a process called:",
				"source": "See Cold Exposure"
			},
			"back": "conduction."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"partial-thickness.",
					"third-degree.",
					"superficial.",
					"full-thickness."
				],
				"question": "Burns associated with lightning strikes are typically:",
				"source": "See Lightning"
			},
			"back": "superficial."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"The tissue damage pathway caused by lightning usually occurs through the skin.",
					"Lightning strikes might cause cardiac dysrhythmias that spontaneously resolve.",
					"Victims who are struck by lightning often experience severe full-thickness burns.",
					"Cervical spine fractures are the most common cause of lightning-related deaths."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding lightning strikes is correct?",
				"source": "See Lightning"
			},
			"back": "Lightning strikes might cause cardiac dysrhythmias that spontaneously resolve."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"water in the lungs following submersion in water.",
					"temporary survival after submersion in water.",
					"death beyond 24 hours after submersion in water.",
					"death from suffocation after submersion in water."
				],
				"question": "Drowning is most accurately defined as:",
				"source": "See Drowning"
			},
			"back": "death from suffocation after submersion in water."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Artificial ventilations can easily be performed in patients with a laryngospasm.",
					"Large amounts of water enter the lungs in a small number of drowning victims.",
					"Patients with a submersion injury might deteriorate rap­idly because of pulmonary injury and cerebral hypoxia.",
					"Hypoxia in the drowning victim initially occurs due to water in the lungs."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding drowning is correct?",
				"source": "See Assessment of Drowning and Diving Emergencies"
			},
			"back": "Patients with a submersion injury might deteriorate rap­idly because of pulmonary injury and cerebral hypoxia."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"have smaller body surface areas.",
					"exhibit poor thermoregulation.",
					"have less body fat.",
					"have relatively smaller heads."
				],
				"question": "Geriatric patients, newborns, and infants are especially prone to hyperthermia because they:",
				"source": "See Heat Exposure"
			},
			"back": "exhibit poor thermoregulation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"a swimmer hyperventilates prior to entering the water.",
					"a diver holds his or her breath during a staged ascent.",
					"a diver holds his or her breath for a long period of time.",
					"a swimmer breathes shallowly before entering the water."
				],
				"question": "Breath-holding syncope is caused by a decreased stimulus to breathe and occurs when:",
				"source": "See Emergency Care for Drowning and Diving Emergencies"
			},
			"back": "a swimmer hyperventilates prior to entering the water."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"nervous system.",
					"cardiovascular system.",
					"renal system.",
					"respiratory system."
				],
				"question": "The venom of a black widow spider is toxic to the:",
				"source": "See Bites and Envenomation"
			},
			"back": "nervous system."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-33-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the diver holds his or her breath during a rapid ascent.",
					"the diver hyperventilates prior to entering the water.",
					"high water pressure forces air into the mediastinum.",
					"the alveoli completely collapse due to high pressure."
				],
				"question": "An air embolism associated with diving occurs when:",
				"source": "See Diving Emergencies"
			},
			"back": "the diver holds his or her breath during a rapid ascent."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-33",
		"label": "Chapter 33"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}